// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What does html stands for?",
    answer: "Hyper Text Markup Language",
    options: [
      "Hyper Text Preprocessor",
      "Hyper Text Markup Language",
      "Hyper Text Multiple Language",
      "Hyper Tool Multi Language"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The correct sequence of HTML tags for starting a webpage is ?",
    answer: "HTML,Head,Title,Body",
    options: [
      "Head,Title,HTML,Body",
      "HTML,Body,Title,Head",
      "HTML,Head,Title,Body",
      "HTML,Title,Head,Body"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is used to create web pages?",
    answer: "HTML",
    options: [
      "HTML",
      "C",
      "JVM",
      "DTD"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "HTML document is saved using ____ extenstion?",
    answer: ".html",
    options: [
      ".htl",
      ".html",
      ".hml",
      ".htnl"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "How many heading tags are supported by HTML?",
    answer: "6",
    options: [
      "3",
      "4",
      "5",
      "6"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "The tags in HTML are ?",
    answer: "not case sensitive",
    options: [
      "case-sensitive",
      "in upper case",
       "not case sensitive",
      "in lower case"
    ]
 },
 {
   numb: 7,
   question: "Which of the following tag is used for inserting the largest heading in HTML ?",
   answer: "< h1 >",
   options: [
     "< h3 >",
     "< h1 >",
     "< h5 >",
     "< h6 >"
   ]
 },
 {
   numb: 8,
   question: "HTML tags are enclosed in-",
   answer: "< and >",
   options: [
     "# and #",
     "{ and }",
     "! and !",
     "< and >"
   ]
 },

 {
   numb: 9,
   question: "CSS stands for ?",
   answer: "Cascading style sheets",
   options: [
     "Cascade style sheets",
     "Color and style sheets",
     "Cascading style sheets",
     "none of the above"
   ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The property in CSS used to change the text color of an element is ?",
    answer: "color",
    options: [
      "bgcolor",
      "color",
      "background-color",
      "back-color"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The CSS property used to specify the transparency of an element is ?",
    answer: "opacity",
    options: [
      "hover",
      "opacity",
      "clearfix",
      "overlay"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which oof the following CSS function allows us to perform calculations ?",
    answer: "calc() function",
    options: [
      "calc() function",
      "calculator() function",
      "calculate() function",
      "cal() function"
    ]
    
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Which type of JavaScript language is ?",
    answer: "object-based",
    options: [
      "object-oriented",
      "object-based",
      "assembly-language",
      "high-level"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "The function and var are known as ?",
    answer: "declaration statements",
    options: [
      "keywords",
      "data types",
      "declaration statements",
      "prototypes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which one of the following keywords is used for defining the function in the javascript ?",
    answer: "function",
    options: [
      "void",
      "init",
      "main",
      "function"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which of the following type of a variable is volatile ?",
    answer: "mutable variable",
    options: [
      "mutable variable",
      "dynamic variable",
      "volatile variable",
      "immutable variable"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Which of the following HTML tag is the special formatting tag ?",
    answer: "< pre >",
    options: [
      "< p >",
      "< b >",
      "< pre >",
      "< br >"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What does the < br > tag add to your webpage ?",
    answer: "line break",
    options: [
      "long break",
      "paragraph break",
      "line break",
      "short break"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which tag will you add to specify a font for your whole page ?",
    answer: "< defaultfont >",
    options: [
      "< defaultfont >",
      "< targetfont >",
      "< basefont >",
      "< font >"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Gif and jpg are the two main type of ?",
    answer: "images",
    options: [
      "animated effects",
      "videos",
      "images",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },

  
];